I'm off then.
那我就出發了
Please take care of yourself.
妳要保重身體喔
I wish you a huge success.
祝妳旗開得勝
Thanks.
嗯
I'll wait for you there, Kita.
我在那邊等妳喔 小北
Kita?
小北
Eh?
咦
Make our country…
妳要在全日本…
No, make the whole world as festive as possible!
不…要在全世界掀起祭典熱潮喔
I will.
嗯
See you at the Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
凱旋門賞見
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《賽馬娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
EPISODE 11: DETERMINATION
(第11話 決心)
I'm so full…
我吃不下了啦…
Oh, no, Diamond. It's late…
糟糕 光鑽 已經這麼晚了…
Oh.
對喔…
I need to get up now.
得快點才行
TAKE FRUITS AND VEGETABLE
(武蔬果店)
-Phew. -You can handle that, love.
-嘿咻 -老婆 那個交給妳了
Morning.
早安
Oh, Kita?
喔 小北
You're as energetic as always.
今天早上也很有精神呢
Eh? You're later than usual today.
哎呀 今天是不是晚了一點呢
Yeah. I overslept.
是啊 不小心睡過頭了
I heard about your new goal, the Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
我聽說妳的目標了喔 凱旋門賞
Eat that and work hard today.
吃了那個 今天也要好好加油喔
Thank you so much.
謝謝你們
"PRIX DE L'ARC DE TRIOMPHE" In Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe,
(凱旋門賞) 那麼請問各位
Japan's best result is securing the runner-up position.
日本賽馬娘在凱旋門賞 所留下的最佳成績為第二名
Only three horse girls have achieved this so far.
而獲得這項成績的賽馬娘共有三位
They are Nakayama Festa, El Condor Pasa, and…?
分別是中山慶典 神鷹 還有一位則是…
-Care to answer, Kitasan Black? -What happened back then?
-那個…北部玄駒 -那個到底是怎麼回事…
My body felt so heavy all of a sudden.
突然覺得身體很沉重
I couldn't even lift my leg.
腳也使不上力…
-Kitasan Black. -I should have
-北部玄駒 -要是平常的話
-Kitasan Black! -been able to…
-應該會更加地…
Yes! Tokai Teio.
有 是東海帝皇
Incorrect.
不對
The right answer is Orfevre.
正確答案是黃金巨匠
It's very important. Memorize it.
這裡很重要 要好好記起來
What? You said Tokai Teio instead of Orfevre?
咦 妳把答案只能是黃金巨匠的問題 答成了東海帝皇嗎
Well, I was spacing out…
沒有啦…我剛好在發呆…
Sigh. You can't slack off because Diamond is no longer here.
真是的 妳是不是因為光鑽不在 就太過鬆懈了啊
Right…
可能喔…
Cheval, you have a huge appetite today.
駿逸今天也很能吃呢
And I'm not full.
不管再怎麼吃也吃不夠
You hit your growth spurt.
是在成長期嗎
I'll wait for you in Arima Kinen, Kitasan.
我在有馬紀念等著妳 北部
Huh?
咦
Before you return from Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe,
在妳從凱旋門賞回來之前
I will win in G1.
我一定會贏下GI優勝
Then, we race against each other in Arima Kinen.
然後在有馬紀念一決勝負吧
Okay.
嗯
I won't let you win that easily.
我不會讓妳贏得如此容易的
I too won my first G1.
我終於也贏下了國內的GI優勝
The upcoming Tenno Sho, Japan Cup, and Arima Kinen,
從現在起的秋季天皇賞 日本盃還有有馬紀念
I will win them all.
我全都會贏的
When are you leaving, Kitasan?
北部何時要出發呢
Huh?
咦
Uhm… I'm still deciding.
那個…我還在思考
If you're serious about it, you must get fully prepared.
要去的話 就要做好萬全的準備
Your previous performance will not be able to secure you the grand prix.
不然以妳那種跑法 是贏不了凱旋門賞的喔
Uhm…
咦
You weren't feeling well during Takarazuka Kinen, were you?
妳在寶塚紀念的時候 狀態沒調整好對吧
I guess so…
是…這個樣子嗎
Cheval?
駿逸
I'm going back for seconds.
我再去拿一份
Again?
哇 妳還要吃啊
If you don't mind, what about this?
不嫌棄的話 這個如何
Kitasan, you didn't eat a lot today.
咦 北部 妳今天吃得很少呢
You didn't even finish your dessert, the katsudon.
連甜點的豬排飯也沒吃
I feel full.
總覺得肚子很飽
Is it because Diamond isn't here?
這也是因為光鑽不在嗎
Perhaps.
可能喔
TOKAI TEIO CAN TEIO OVERTAKE EMPEROR?
(東海帝皇) (帝王能超越皇帝嗎)
Morning, Diamond.
早安 光鑽…
All right.
好
TRAINING BEGINS TODAY
(今天開始要來練習了)
IT'S RAINY TODAY, SO WE ARE TRAINING INDOORS.
(這裡是雨天 今天要做室內訓練)
Wait for me, Diamond. I'll come to you real soon.
光鑽 妳要等我 我馬上就去找妳…
Go, go, go.
爆進爆進爆進
"DON'T USE YOUR PHONE WHILE WALKING" Sorry.
(請勿邊走路邊滑手機) 抱歉
I didn't watch where I was going, so I…
是我邊走邊看手機 才沒注意到妳
No, I should be the one apologizing.
不會 該道歉的人是我
Anyway, I must go now.
那麼我還有事 先走了
Okay.
是
Good. The lap time is great.
好 時間還不錯
Huh?
咦
What's the matter, Kita?
小北 怎麼了
Sorry. I must run another lap.
不好意思 我再跑一趟
This is weird. What's going on?
奇怪 這是怎麼回事…
I feel like…
有種…
Not bad, Kita.
嗯 還不錯喔 北部
My final sprint isn't fast enough.
那個 我覺得最後的衝刺 好像還不夠快
But you completed it in around the same time.
但是時間一樣好喔
Why? Is something out of the ordinary?
怎麼了 跟平常有什麼不同嗎
Let me run another lap.
我再去跑跑看
Wait.
先等一下…
Don't force yourself if you don't feel well.
要是覺得有異樣就別勉強自己
Perhaps you're still tired from Takarazuka Kinen.
說不定是寶塚紀念的疲勞 還沒完全恢復
Let's call it a day here. You should get some rest.
今天就到此為止 早點休息吧
But…
可是…
Kitasan.
北部
All right. I'll go back then.
我明白了 那我就先告辭了
She's…
那個傢伙…
Awesome! You broke today's record in your last lap.
不錯嘛 在最後跑出了今天的最佳成績
Yay!
成功了
Have some water.
來 喝水
Thanks.
謝謝
That's all for today.
好 今天的練習就到此為止
Okay.
是
But I want to run one more lap.
不過 我要再去跑一趟
The bottle!
瓶子啊
And she continues to run…
那孩子還能這樣奔跑啊…
How refreshing.
清清爽爽
LUNCHTIME!
(現在要來吃午飯了)
WHEN ARE YOU COMING TO FRANCE?
(決定好何時要來法國了嗎)
DIAMOND, I THINK SOMETHING'S WRONG WITH MY BODY.
(光鑽 我跟妳說喔) (我的身體好像怪怪…)
Take it.
給妳
I wonder how many sides you can solve.
不曉得妳能轉出幾面呢
I'LL LET YOU KNOW ONCE I PLAN EVERYTHING. GOOD NIGHT.
(等行程決定好再跟妳說喔 晚安)
I'm fine.
沒事的…
My body is fine.
沒事的 我沒問題的…
I'll be fine.
我一定沒問題的…
I sleep well. I eat well.
睡好覺 吃飽飯
My body is in tip-top shape.
將身體調整至絕佳狀態
If I train harder, I can…
只要…只要勤加練習 一定…
If you train harder, you'll regain your form.
只要勤加練習 就能回到原本的狀態
Gold Ship?
黃金船
But it never comes back, does it?
但是…狀態一直回不來對吧
No matter how hard you try or train.
不管怎麼練習或用了多少方法
How do you…
為什麼…
Because I've been through that.
因為我也有這種經驗
Huh?
咦
Somehow, I am not able to accelerate.
不知從何時開始就使不上勁
I can't control my emotions.
無法自在地控制自己的情緒
I can't start properly.
也無法順利衝出閘門
Kitasan Black.
北部玄駒
You have reached your peak.
妳已經過了巔峰期了
DIAMOND, I THINK SOMETHING'S WRONG WITH MY BODY.
(光鑽 我跟妳說喔) (我的身體好像怪怪…)
Huh?
咦
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《賽馬娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
I see.
這樣啊…
I truly hope you're wrong this time.
我倒是希望這是妳搞錯了
So in Takarazuka Kinen, you were…
所以 寶塚紀念時的表現也是…
Mr. Trainer.
訓練師先生
Can I continue racing?
我應該…還能跑吧
After you reach your peak, you might still retain your strength.
當然了 雖說過了巔峰期 但這並不代表實力馬上就會下降
But it will dwindle.
但奔跑實力確實是會逐漸衰退
When does that happen?
那會從什麼時候開始呢…
Post-peak, things might play out differently for every horse girl.
過了巔峰期的賽馬娘 每個人的演變都有所不同
Some are downright too weak to compete.
有些人會突然衰退到無法比賽
Some see their strength fade away over the course of their career.
也有人的能力是緩緩降低
But some regain their form.
其中也有人像是脫胎換骨般 重拾了奔跑的力量
That means…
這樣的話…
That means I can continue racing, right?
我也有可能還能繼續跑對吧
Yes.
是啊…
But what about Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe?
但是…凱旋門賞要怎麼辦
Many horse girls competed in it but they couldn't win it.
這是眾多賽馬娘向其挑戰 卻始終無法達成的夙願
To win it
要是贏下凱旋門賞
is to rewrite our history.
肯定能改寫日本賽馬娘的歷史吧
But there are some caveats too. You'll be far from home
但是長距離的移動 以及與賽場的適性等
and you might not be able to adapt to their turf.
同時伴隨著這些風險也是事實
Think carefully before you decide.
妳好好考慮 再做出決定吧
Don't leave any regrets.
不要留下遺憾
I see.
我明白了…
I should go now.
我先告辭了
In fact,
但是…
I don't want you to participate in your current state.
我不希望讓現在的妳去
FUKUNAGA COMMERCIAL STREET
(福永商店街)
I have reached my peak, huh?
過了巔峰期…
So that's the reason.
原來…是這樣啊…
What do I do?
怎麼辦…
Diamond, I…
光鑽…我…
Done!
好 完成了
So this is what it's like.
原來是這種感覺啊
-Woah. -Open it.
-好厲害 -拉開來
Up. Further up.
再上去 再上去一點
Wait.
等一下
It's so big.
好大喔
It's done.
弄好了呢
"MAKE FRANCE FESTIVE, KITASAN BLACK!"
(凱旋門賞 舉辦祭典吧 北部玄駒)
Yes.
是啊
I wonder if Kita will like it.
不知道小北看到會不會開心呢
Thank you everyone for your help.
謝謝大家的幫忙啊
Don't mention it.
不會啦 小事一件啦
It's a very beautiful victory banner.
是個很棒的慶賀布條呢
Kita is going to Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
那個小北要去挑戰凱旋門賞啊
It feels surreal.
感覺好像在作夢一樣
You know,
但是啊…
while I believe Kita will put up an impressive performance in France,
我覺得在法國奔跑的小北 肯定會很帥氣
I still think
但是啊…
that Fuchu is where she belongs.
我還是覺得 府中才是最適合小北的地方
Yeah.
是啊
I want to be in the spectators' stand and cheer for her in G1 during autumn.
真想在秋季GI的比賽裡 站在觀眾席為她加油呢
We all want to see the moment Kita defends her title in Tenno Sho.
大家都很想看到呢 小北連霸春秋天皇賞的瞬間
I won't be able to see Kita for a while.
會有段時間見不到小北了呢
I'll miss her a lot.
真令人寂寞
I give her bananas whenever she jogs past here.
每天給跑過這裡的小北香蕉
And during the weekend, I watch and cheer for her in the race.
到了週末再去看有她參加的比賽 為她加油
She's part of our life now.
小北總是充斥在 我們的每天的生活中呢
MAKE FRANCE FESTIVE, KITASAN BLACK!
(凱旋門賞 舉辦祭典吧 北部玄駒)
TRAINER'S OFFICE
(訓練師室)
So that's your decision?
是嗎…妳做出決定了嗎
Yes.
是的
Everyone wants to see the way I run.
大家都對我說 說想要看著我奔跑的模樣
that I'm in their everyday life.
說我充斥在他們每天的生活中
I'm not going to France anymore.
我不去法國了
If my time is running up,
如果留給我的時間真的不多的話
I want to use whatever time I have to perform before everyone.
我想要將剩下的比賽 全部展現在大家的面前
Kitasan…
北部…
So sign me up for whatever races.
所以 請盡可能地為我報名比賽吧
Be it Tenno Sho, Japan Cup, or Arima Kinen,
不論是秋季天皇賞 還是日本盃 或是有馬紀念
I want to participate in them.
我全都要參加
Then try to get the veteran's triple crown.
那就來挑戰看看吧 秋季資深三冠
Huh?
咦
Only two horse girls have ever won
贏下這三場GI比賽的賽馬娘
these three G1 races.
至今只有兩位
Besides, you may just win both spring and autumn Tenno Sho.
而且秋季天皇賞 還關係到妳的同年春秋連霸
What do you think?
意下如何
Sure.
是
Let's start from the Tenno Sho in autumn then.
好 那就先從秋季天皇賞開始吧
Mr. Trainer, I want to win it
訓練師先生 我要贏下天皇賞
and prove to everyone that I can still run.
向所有人証明 我還能繼續跑
Good.
好
All right then. I'll work very hard!
好 我要加油
Yeah.
嗯
Sorry that I can't be there with you.
抱歉 不能跟妳一起跑了
Yes.
嗯…
Let's work hard together.
彼此互相加油吧
Bye.
再見
KITASAN BLACK WITHDREW FROM PRIX DE L'ARC DE TRIOMPHE
(北部玄駒逃避凱旋門賞)
SATONO DIAMOND, 15TH IN PRIX DE L'ARC DE TRIOMPHE
(里見光鑽 凱旋門賞 第十五名)
Due to the typhoon, the sky is cloudy.
因颱風來襲而天色昏暗
The turf is affected by the downpour.
賽場因持續降雨而地質不良
Despite the bad weather,
即便如此
fans gather here in Tokyo Racecourse
眾多粉絲為了一睹她們的身影 依然來到此處
to witness their performance.
來到這個東京競馬場
We have a stellar lineup today. Eight G1 horse girls in total.
這一戰的陣容豪華 聚集了8位GI賽馬娘
And the highly-anticipated one is Kitasan Black, who has five G1 wins.
其中最受矚目的 應該就是GI5勝的北部玄駒吧
Indeed.
是啊
As long as she maintains her lead as usual, we're in for a treat.
只要如同往常一般領先在前 應該就能見識到一場精彩比賽
How will the winner of Takarazuka Kinen, Satono Crown, fare?
贏下寶塚紀念的里見皇冠如何呢
She knows how to deal with wet turf.
畢竟她很擅長對付這種濕軟場地
I can't wait to see her performance today.
很期待她在今天的比賽中 會如何表現
Tenno Sho will begin soon.
秋季天皇賞 即將開始
Tenno Sho.
秋季天皇賞
A 2,000-meter lap under rain.
雨中的2000公尺
It begins now!
現在開始了
Eh? Kitasan Black…
北部玄駒她居然…
She's off to a bad start and falls behind.
她起跑失誤 慢了大家一步
Everyone is vying for the lead on the muddy path.
所有人在泥濘賽道上爭奪領先位置
Did Kitasan Black miss the timing because of the rain?
是這因為這場雨掌握不到時機嗎
She fumbled her start.
北部玄駒的起跑相當失常
In today's race, she'll have to catch up from behind.
今天的比賽 她將在後方伺機而動
Kitasan is off to a bad start.
北部起步慢了一步
This is looking grim.
情況很不樂觀呢
Heading to the first bend,
好的 來到了最初的彎道
No. 11, Ivory Tower.
11號象牙之塔
No. 1, Hard Control.
1號堅定掌控
Kitasan Black is in this position.
北部玄駒則是在這個位置
Tenno Sho, the mid-range grand event that combines classics
這場混合了經典級與資深級的 中距離最強賽馬娘的傳統決定戰
and veteran horse girls.
秋季天皇賞
Huh? Why?
怎麼突然說這個
In this race, the distance between the first and the second bend is 100m.
這場比賽 從最初到第二彎道 大約只有短短的100公尺
Staying in the inside line is advantageous
雖說內側較為有利
but don't forget that the track is all muddy because of the typhoon.
但今天是颱風來襲的超泥濘賽道
Everyone will avoid the inside line.
所有選手 都避開泥濘的內側跑道奔跑
Which means that they will spread out at the bend and form a cluster.
導致選手們在彎道散得比以往更開 使得領先隊伍混成一團
Kitasan Black, who hit the gate and got off to a bad start,
對撞到閘門而 晚人一步起跑的北部玄駒來說
will have a hard time catching up.
肯定會更加辛苦
This is a tough battle.
這將會是艱困的一戰
You sure have a pair of keen eyes.
你看得還真清楚
Heading into the stretch,
進入了非終點直線
Ivory Tower is in the lead.
領先的是象牙之塔
No. 18, Moon Hero, closes in from the flank.
從外側追上的是18號明月英雄
Satono Crown stays in the inside line.
里見皇冠奔跑在內側
They just completed a 1,000-meter lap.
通過了前半的1000公尺
Indeed, their performance is affected. The completion time is 64 seconds.
賽道不良果然有影響 時間停在64秒
Everyone is struggling.
感覺大家很辛苦呢
This kind of track…
這種賽道狀態…
The Kitasan Black I know
要是平時的北部玄駒
does not care if the track is in her favour or not.
這種稍微不擅長的賽道 她才不會放在眼裡
Passing through the third bend,
現在通過第三彎道
Ivory Tower is in the lead.
領先的是象牙之塔
No, Beyond Lightspeed overtook her.
不 現在變成了超越光速
Good.
好
Kitasan?
北部
What's with that face of determination?
這氣魄是怎麼回事
I won't lose to you.
我絕對不會輸給妳的
Satono Crown closes in and takes the second spot.
里見皇冠追上 成為了第二名
Which horse girl can conquer
究竟是哪位賽馬娘
this muddy track and obtain the trophy?
能夠稱霸這條超泥濘賽道 得到秋季獎盃呢
Heading to the last bend, they only have 600 meters left.
現在通過最終彎道 剩下不到600公尺了
Everyone is getting ready for the final sprint.
所有賽馬娘 同時開始進行最終衝刺
They avoid the muddy inside line.
賽馬娘們避開了泥濘的最內側跑道
Beyond Lightspeed is still in the lead.
好的 領先的是超越光速
Perhaps everyone is exhausted from running on a slippery track,
不知道是不是 在濕滑的跑道上用光了體力
no one can overtake her.
其他的GI賽馬娘們追不上她
Wait. Satono Crown speeds up.
居然 里見皇冠在這裡追了上去
She loves a muddy track so she closes in decisively.
在這個她最擅長的泥濘賽道上 颯爽地追了上去
Good.
好
Satono Crown is about to secure the lead.
里見皇冠 將要取得領先了
No. Right now,
不對 就在這時
Kitasan Black is here.
她來了 北部玄駒來了
Using her powerful limbs, she runs on the muddy inside line that everyone avoids.
她以她強健的腳力 克服了大家避開的最內側泥地
Kitasan Black closes the gap.
北部玄駒 一口氣追了上來
Crown!
皇冠
Go!
衝啊…
Go, Kitasan!
衝啊 北部
Kitasan Black is relentless.
北部玄駒 瘋狂追趕
She has the lead now.
衝到了領先位置
Victory is mine.
勝利將會是我的
400 meters left.
剩下不到400公尺
Kitasan is in the lead.
北部領先…
Behind her is Satono Crown.
里見皇冠緊追在後
Can Kitasan Black outrun others
北部玄駒會甩開她們
or will Satono Crown overtake her spot?
還是里見皇冠會超越她呢
Kitasan.
北部
That's my chance.
就是這裡
Can Kitasan maintain her lead?
北部撐得下去嗎
Satono Crown went to the inside line. Can she overtake Kitasan?
在這時衝入內線的里見皇冠 能超越她嗎
Crown is here.
皇冠來了…
The gap is diminishing. Kitasan tries to secure her lead.
差距逐漸縮小 北部還在苦撐
They make a beeline for fame and glory
這個艱難的超泥濘賽道
on this muddy path in Tokyo Racecourse.
在東京競馬場的直線裡衝向榮耀
Everyone is caked with mud.
渾身泥濘的纏鬥
Who will hold the trophy despite the storm?
在穿越暴風雨後 能得到秋季獎盃的人
Will it be Kitasan Black or Satono Crown?
究竟會是北部玄駒 還是里見皇冠呢
You can do this, Crown.
皇冠 加油啊
Go!
衝啊…
But Kitasan still has the lead.
但是 領先的是北部
It's Kitasan Black!
是北部玄駒
Kitasan Black crosses the finishing line!
北部玄駒 衝過終點
We were all misled by Kitasan's bad start.
結果最初的賽況只是我們杞人憂天
What an amazing performance, Kitasan Black!
太精彩了 北部玄駒
She was off to a bad start
難得看到她起跑失誤
but it was no bother at all.
最後才明白根本無需擔心
She claims the soaked track with her speed and endurance,
憑藉著實力 稱霸了颱風來襲的糟糕賽場
as if she's telling everyone that she's the strongest in the Twinkle Series.
彷彿訴說著 這就是閃光系列賽最強賽馬娘般
She won beautifully.
漂亮地贏下了這場比賽
She won Tenno Sho.
她奪下了秋季天皇的獎盃
She won the spring and the autumn Tenno Sho.
同時也達成同年春秋天皇賞連霸
-Wow. Kitasan is simply too awesome. -After Special Week and T M Opera O,
-好厲害 太厲害了 北部 -繼特別週及好歌劇後
Kitasan Black is the third to obtain this achievement.
她在偉大賽馬娘的歷史中 刻下了自己的名字
Kitasan Black!
北部玄駒
She completed the race in 2 minutes, 8.3 seconds.
完賽時間為2分8秒3
She overcame the less-than-ideal track condition
以實力克服如此艱困狀況
and did not give up the lead to Satono Crown.
直到最後都沒讓 緊追在後的里見皇冠超越自己
This is Kitasan Black's sixth G1 win.
北部玄駒 這是她的GI第6勝
I see it now…
原來如此…